[
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"\"Now is the winter of our discontent\" is a line from which Shakespearian play?", "answer":0,"answers":["Richard III", "Romeo and Juliet", "Macbeth"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"\"Our Town\" is a play by whom?", "answer":0,"answers":["Thornton Wilder"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"\"The Diary of Anne Frank\" was first published in English under what title?", "answer":0,"answers":["The diary of a young girl"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A band of painted or sculpted decoration, often at the top of a wall.", "answer":0,"answers":["A frieze"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A composition made of cut and pasted pieces of materials, sometimes with images added by the artist.", "answer":0,"answers":["Collage"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A decorative art movement that emerged in the late nineteenth century. Characterized by dense assymmetrical ornamentation in sinuous forms, it is often symbolic and of an erotic nature.", "answer":0,"answers":["Art nouveau"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A design style prevalent during the 1920s and 1930s, characterized by a sleek use of straight lines and slender forms.", "answer":0,"answers":["Art deco"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A European movement beginning in France in the thirteenth century. The artworks are characterized by a linear, graceful, elegant style more naturalistic than that which had existed previously in Europe.", "answer":0,"answers":["Gothic", "Renaissance", "Romanesque"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A European movement of the late eighteenth to mid-nineteenth century. In reaction to neoclassicism, it focused on emotion over reason, and on spontaneous expression.", "answer":0,"answers":["Romanticism", "Gothic", "Romanesque"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A European style developed in France in the late eleventh century. Its sculpture is ornamental, stylized and complex.", "answer":0,"answers":["Romanesque", "Gothic", "Neoclassicism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A European style of the late eighteenth and early nineteenth centuries. Its elegant, balanced works revived the order and harmony of ancient Greek and Roman art.", "answer":0,"answers":["Neoclassicism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A figurative movement that emerged in the United States and Britain in the late 1960s and 1970s. The subject matter, usually everyday scenes, is portrayed in an extremely detailed, exacting style. It is also called _superrealism_, especially when referring to sculpture.", "answer":0,"answers":["Photorealism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A flat board used by a painter to mix and hold colors, traditionally oblong, with a hole for the thumb.", "answer":0,"answers":["Palette"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A group of American painters who united out of opposition to academic standards in the early twentieth century.", "answer":0,"answers":["The eight"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A group of English painters formed in 1848. These artists attempted to recapture the style of painting preceding Raphael. They rejected industrialized England and focused on painting from nature, producing detailed, colorful works.", "answer":0,"answers":["Pre-Raphaelite Brotherhood"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A large painting or decoration done on a wall.", "answer":0,"answers":["Mural"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A late-nineteenth-century French school of painting. It focused on transitory visual impressions, often painted directly from nature, with an emphasis on the changing effects of light and color.", "answer":0,"answers":["Impressionism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A method of painting developed by Seurat and Signac in the 1880s. It used dabs of pure color that were intended to mix in the eyes of viewers rather than on the canvas. It is also called _divisionism_ or _neoimpressionism_.", "answer":0,"answers":["Pointillism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A method of producing images or letters from sheets of cardboard, metal, or other materials from which forms have been cut away.", "answer":0,"answers":["Stenciling"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A method of watercolor painting, but prepared with a more gluey base, producing a less transparent effect.", "answer":0,"answers":["Gouache"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement in American painting and sculpture that originated in the late 1950s. It emphasized pure, reduced forms and strict, systematic compositions.", "answer":0,"answers":["Minimalism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement in European painting in the seventeenth and early eighteenth centuries, characterized by violent movement, strong emotion, and dramatic lighting and coloring.", "answer":0,"answers":["Baroque"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement of the 1920s and 1930s that began in France. It explored the unconscious, often using images from dreams. It used spontaneous techniques and featured unexpected juxtapositions of objects.", "answer":0,"answers":["Surrealism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement of the 1960s and 1970s that emphasized the artistic idea over the art object. It attempted to free art from the confines of the gallery and the pedestal.", "answer":0,"answers":["Conceptual art"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement that began in Britain and the United States in the 1950s. It used the images and techniques of mass media, advertising, and popular culture, often in an ironic way.", "answer":0,"answers":["Pop art"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement, c. 1915-23, that rejected accepted aesthetic standards. It aimed to create antiart and nonart, often employing a sense of the absurd.", "answer":0,"answers":["Dadaism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A painting movement that flourished in France in the 1880s and 1980s in which subject matter was suggested rather than directly presented. It featured decorative, stylized, and evocative images.", "answer":0,"answers":["Symbolism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A painting or drawing executed in a single color.", "answer":0,"answers":["Monochrome"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A painting technique using pigments mixed with egg yolk and water. It produces clear, pure colors.", "answer":0,"answers":["Tempera"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A print made by carving on a wood block, which is then inked and printed.", "answer":0,"answers":["Woodcut"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A printing process in which ink impressions are taken from a flat stone or metal plate prepared with a greasy substance, such as an oily crayon.", "answer":0,"answers":["Litography"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A realistic style of painting in which everyday life forms the subject matter, as distinguished from religious or historical painting.", "answer":0,"answers":["Genre painting"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A representation of a human or an animal form.", "answer":0,"answers":["Figure"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A russian abstract movement begun in the early twentieth century. It employs an analytic vision based on fragmentation and multiple viewpoints.", "answer":0,"answers":["Cubism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A Russian abstract movement originated by Malevich c. 1913. It was characterized by flat geometric shapes on plain backgrounds and emphasized the spiritual qualities of pure form.", "answer":0,"answers":["Suprematism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A single print made from a metal or glass plate on which an image has been represented in paint, ink, etc.", "answer":0,"answers":["Monotype"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A soft, subdued color; a drawing stick made of ground pigments, chalk, and gum water.", "answer":0,"answers":["Pastel"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A style, c. 1520-1600, that arose in reaction to the harmony and proportion of the High Renaissance. It featured elongated, contorted poses, crowded canvases, and harsh lighting and coloring.", "answer":0,"answers":["Mannerism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A technique in abstract painting developed in the 1950s. It focuses on the lyrical effects of large areas of color, often poured or stained onto the canvas.", "answer":0,"answers":["Color field painting"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A technique of engraving, using a sharp-pointed needle, that produces a furrowed edge resulting in a print with soft, velvety lines.", "answer":0,"answers":["Drypoint"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A termed coined by British art critic Roger Fry to refer to a group of nine-teenth century painters, who were dissatisfied with the limitations of impressionism. It has since been used to refer to various reactions against impressionism, such as fauvism and expressionism.", "answer":0,"answers":["Postimpressionism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"According To \"The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy\" what number is the answer to everything?\"", "answer":0,"answers":["Forty Two"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"An abstract movement in Europe and the United States, begun in the mid-1950s, based on the effect of optical patterns.", "answer":0,"answers":["Op art"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"An artwork humoously excaggerating the qualities, defects, or pecularities of a person or idea.", "answer":0,"answers":["Caricature"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"An eighteenth-century European style, originating in France. In reaction to the grandeur and massiveness of the baroque, it employed refined, elegant, highly decorative forms.", "answer":0,"answers":["Rococco"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"An etching tecnique in which a solution of asphalt or resin is used on the plate. It produces prints with rich, gray tones.", "answer":0,"answers":["Aquatint"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"An italian movement c.1909-1919. It attempted to integrate the dynamism of the machine age into art.", "answer":0,"answers":["Futurism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Artwork, usually paintings, characterized by a simplified style, nonscientific perspective, and bold colors. The artists are generally not professionally trained.", "answer":0,"answers":["Naive art"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"As what did H.G. Wells refer to Adolf Hitler?", "answer":0,"answers":["A certifiable lunatic"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"At which railway station does Harry Potter catch the Hogwart's Express at platform 9 and 3 quarters?", "answer":0,"answers":["King's Cross"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Author of \"The Lighthouse\" and \"Eminent Victorians\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Virginia Woolf"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Author of such works as Gravity's Rainbow, V, The Crying of Lot 49 and most recently, Mason & Dixon?", "answer":0,"answers":["Thomas Pynchon"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Bob Kane created who?", "answer":0,"answers":["Batman"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"By what name is the great italian sculptor & artist Buonarroti better known?", "answer":0,"answers":["Michelangelo"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Captain Hook, Tiger Lily, and Tinker Bell are characters in what story?", "answer":0,"answers":["Peter Pan"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Douglas Adams is famous for writing what?", "answer":0,"answers":["The hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Dr. Seuss wrote this book: The Cat in the ______.", "answer":0,"answers":["Hat"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Edgar Allan Poe wrote a famous poem about this animal.", "answer":0,"answers":["Raven"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Eliza Doolittle appears in which play?", "answer":0,"answers":["Pygmalion/My Fair Lady"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Faulkner penned this book with 4 distinctive sections: the Benjy section, Quentin's section, Jason and then Dilsey's sections.", "answer":0,"answers":["The Sound and the Fury"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"For what is Dame Margott Fonteyn famous?", "answer":0,"answers":["Ballet Dancing"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"For which novel was Boris Pasternak awarded the 1958 Nobel Prize, an award he declined?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dr Zhivago"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"French impressionist Claude _____", "answer":0,"answers":["Monet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Frodo is chosen to deliver The Ring into the heart of what?", "answer":0,"answers":["Mount doom"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"From the french word \"fauve\", meaning \"wild beast\". A style adopted by artists associated with Matisse, c. 1905-1908. They painted in a spontaneous manner, using bold colors.", "answer":0,"answers":["Fauvism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"From the Hebrew word for \"prophet\". A group of French painters active in the 1890s who worked in a subjective, sometimes mystical style, stressing flat areas of color and pattern.", "answer":0,"answers":["Nabis"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"Goodnight, goodnight! Parting is such sweet sorrow, That I should say goodnight till it be morrow.\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Romeo and Juliet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"To be or not to be?\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Hamlet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"What in a name? That which we call a rose, by any other name would smell as sweet.\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Romeo and Juliet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"From whom did Bilbo obtain The Ring", "answer":0,"answers":["Gollum"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Gandalf's elven name.", "answer":0,"answers":["Mithrandir"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Ground chalk or plaster mixed with glue, used as a base coat for tempera and oil painting.", "answer":0,"answers":["Gesso"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Group of American artists from 1908 to 1918. Their work featured scenes of urban realism.", "answer":0,"answers":["Ash Can School"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"H.G. Wells novel where Earth is invaded by Martians.", "answer":0,"answers":["War of the worlds"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"He penned the founding novel of the utopian genre, \"Utopia.\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Sir Thomas More"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"He wrote Ulysses, Giacomo Joyce, Dubliners and Finnegans Wake, among others.", "answer":0,"answers":["James Joyce"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"His many romantic odes include \"Ode to Melancholy\" and \"Ode to a Graecian Urn\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Keats"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Homer wrote this account of the Trojan War.", "answer":0,"answers":["Iliad"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How is Jack Dawkins otherwise known as in a Dickens novel?", "answer":0,"answers":["Artful Dodger"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How is Mrs William Heelis better known?", "answer":0,"answers":["Beatrix Potter"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How is Samuel Clemens better known?", "answer":0,"answers":["Mark Twain"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How many books are there in Anne Rice's vampire series?", "answer":0,"answers":["Five"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How Many Holes Are There On A Traditional Artists Pallette?", "answer":0,"answers":["One"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How many lines are in a sonnet?", "answer":0,"answers":["Fourteen"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How many plays is Shakespeare generally credited with today?", "answer":0,"answers":["Thirty seven"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How many stories did enid blyton publish in 1959?", "answer":0,"answers":["Fifty nine"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How many tales are there in Chaucers Canterbury tales?", "answer":0,"answers":["23"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"How old was Adrian Mole when he began writing his secret diary?", "answer":0,"answers":["13 & Three Quarters"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"A Christmas Carol\", how many ghosts visited Scrooge?", "answer":0,"answers":["Four"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"A Christmas Carol\", what was the name of the miser?", "answer":0,"answers":["Ebenezer Scrooge"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"Alice In Wonderland\", who never stopped sobbing?", "answer":0,"answers":["Mock Turtle"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"Romeo and Juliet\", about what was Mercutio's long monologue?", "answer":0,"answers":["Queen Mab"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"Romeo and Juliet\", who gave a long monologue about Queen Mab?", "answer":0,"answers":["Mercutio"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"Romeo and Juliet\", who said \"I have a faint cold, fear thrills through my veins\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Juliet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"Romeo and Juliet\", who says \"Make the bridal bed in that dim monument where Tybalt lies\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Juliet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"Romeo and Juliet\", who says \"what must be must be\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Juliet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"The Canterbury Tales\" at which tavern do the story tellers assemble?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Tabard"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In \"The Rhyme Of The Ancient Mariner\", which bird is shot", "answer":0,"answers":["An Albatross"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In 1526 Hans Holbein became the official portrait painter of which english king?", "answer":0,"answers":["Henry VIII"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In 2007 who topped the best sellers non fiction list with \"Born to be riled\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Jeremy Clarkson"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In a general sense, refers to objective representation. More specifically, a nineteenth century movement, especially in France, that rejected idealized academic styles in favor of everyday subjects.", "answer":0,"answers":["Realism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In HG Wells \"The Time Machine,\" two races of the future are the child-like Eloi, and the underground monsters called the ____?\"", "answer":0,"answers":["Morlocks"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In one of Donald Horne's novels, as what was Australia dubbed?", "answer":0,"answers":["The lucky country"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In one of Donald Horne's novels, which was \"the lucky country\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Australia"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In painting, a thin layer of translucent color.", "answer":0,"answers":["Wash"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In painting, a work made of several panels or scenes joined together. A diptych has two panels, a triptych, three.", "answer":0,"answers":["Polyptych"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In painting, the degree of lightness or darkness in a color.", "answer":0,"answers":["Values"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In sculpting, the cutting of a form from a solid, hard material such as stone or wood, in contrast to the technique of modeling.", "answer":0,"answers":["Carving"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In sculpture, the building up of form using a soft medium such as clay or wax, as distinguished from carving. In painting and drawing, using color and lighting variations to produce a three-dimensional effect.", "answer":0,"answers":["Modeling"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In sculpture, the projection of an image or form from its background. Sculpture formed in this manner is described as high relief or low relief (bas-relief), depending on the degree of projection. In painting or drawing, the apparent projection of parts conveying the illusion of three dimensions.", "answer":0,"answers":["Relief"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In Swifts \"Gullivers Travels\" what is Gullivers profession", "answer":0,"answers":["Surgeon"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In the book \"The Secret Diary Of Adrian Mole\", what was the name of adrian's girllfriend?", "answer":0,"answers":["Pandora"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In the Dr Seuss books, which elephant hatched an egg?", "answer":0,"answers":["Horton"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In what book would you find a Hefalump?", "answer":0,"answers":["Winnie the Pooh"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In what field of study would you find \"flying buttresses\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Architecture"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In what opera would you find Lt. Pinkerton?", "answer":0,"answers":["Madame butterfly"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In what science fiction novel do Duke Leto Atreidea & the Harkonnens feature?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dune"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In what work does the HAL 9000 appear?", "answer":0,"answers":["2001, A Space Odyssey"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which book did four ghosts visit Scrooge?", "answer":0,"answers":["A Christmas Carol"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which book is Scheherazade a story teller?", "answer":0,"answers":["Arabian Nights"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which book which is also a film has the characters Pod, Arrietty, Homily & Peagreen?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Borrowers"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which book would you find the characters Desinov & Dolokhov?", "answer":0,"answers":["Tolstoy's War & Peace"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which British national daily newspaper does Rupert The Bear appear?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Daily Express"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which century did artists first start painting on canvas?", "answer":0,"answers":["15th Century"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which city is The Encyclopediaa Britanica published?", "answer":0,"answers":["Chicago"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which city will you find the largest opera house in the world?", "answer":0,"answers":["New York , The Metropolitan Opera"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which country was John Constable born?", "answer":0,"answers":["Suffolk"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which Gilbert & Sullivan operetta does Nakipoo appear?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Mikado"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which John Steinbeck story features the slow-witted Lennie and his friend George?", "answer":0,"answers":["Of Mice & Men"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which novel was it the job of the \"Fireman\" to burn books?", "answer":0,"answers":["Fahrenheit 451"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which novels does Bilbo Baggins appear?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Hobbit/ Lord Of The Rings"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which shakespearean play would you find the clown Costard?", "answer":0,"answers":["Love's Labour Lost"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which shakespearean tragedy Does Laertes appear?", "answer":0,"answers":["Hamlet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"In which story does the schoolboy \"Piggy\" star?", "answer":0,"answers":["Lord Of The Flies"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Meaning \"fool the eye\" in french. In painting, the fine, detailed rendering of objects to convey the illusion that the painted forms are real and three-dimensional.", "answer":0,"answers":["Trompe l'oeil"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Meaning \"fresh\" in italian. The technique of painting on moist lime plaster with colors ground in water.", "answer":0,"answers":["Fresco"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Meaning \"rebirth\" in french. Refers to Europe c. 1400-1600. The style began in Italy and stressed the forms of classical antiquity, a realistic representation of space based on scientific perspective, and secular subjects.", "answer":0,"answers":["Renaissance"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Movement in painting, originating in New York City in the 1940s. It emphasized spontaneous personal expression, freedom from accepted artistic values, surface quallities of paint, and the act of painting itself.", "answer":0,"answers":["Abstract expressionism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Name the author of \"The Catcher in the Rye\"", "answer":0,"answers":["J.D. Salinger"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Name the author of his famous and only novel \"Doctor Zhivago\", which presents a panoramic view of Russian society at the time of the 1917 Revolution.", "answer":0,"answers":["Boris Pasternak"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Name the famous greek writer of Fables", "answer":0,"answers":["Aesop"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Name the philadelphian artist who introduced the world to pop art", "answer":0,"answers":["Andy Warhol"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Name the Shakespeare play from this ultra short plot summary: Urged on by his wife, a man murders his king in order to take his place.", "answer":0,"answers":["Macbeth"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Name the three Bronte Sisters", "answer":0,"answers":["Charlotte, Emily & Anne"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Name the Tibetan mountain retreat featured in \"The Lost Horizon\"", "answer":0,"answers":["Shangri-La"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Of which famous London landmark was Sir Alfred Gilbert the sculptor?", "answer":0,"answers":["Eros"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"On a represented form, a point of most intense light.", "answer":0,"answers":["Highlight"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"On what book was 'Three Days Of The Condor' based?", "answer":0,"answers":["Six Days Of The Condor"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Paint applied very thickly. It often projects from the picture surface.", "answer":0,"answers":["Impasto"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Painting in which natural scenery is the subject.", "answer":0,"answers":["Landscape"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Principally, of what nationality were the impressionist painters?", "answer":0,"answers":["French"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Reducing or distorting in order to represent three-dimensional space as perceived by the eye, according to the rules of perspective.", "answer":0,"answers":["Foreshortening"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Referring to the principles of Greek and Roman art of antiquity with its emphasis on harmony, proportion, balance, and simplicity. In a general sense, it refers to art based on accepted standards of beauty.", "answer":0,"answers":["Classicism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Refers to art that uses emphasis and distortion to communicate emotion. More specifically, it refers to early twentieth-century northern European art, especially in Germany c. 1905-23.", "answer":0,"answers":["Expressionism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Sherlock Holmes lived at 221b _____ street?", "answer":0,"answers":["Baker"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Spanish modernist and cubist Pablo _____", "answer":0,"answers":["Picasso"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Stephen King's: \"Pet ________\".", "answer":0,"answers":["Semetary"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Stephen King's: \"Salem's _________\".", "answer":0,"answers":["Lot"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Stephen King's: \"The Dead ________\".", "answer":0,"answers":["Zone"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The ____ ____ school of poetry includes poets such as Frank O'Hara, John Ashbery and Kenneth Koch", "answer":0,"answers":["New York"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The ____ generation included such authors as Jack Kerouac, William S. Burroughs and Allen Ginsburg.", "answer":0,"answers":["Beat"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The book \"Wamyouruijoshou\" was the first to use what word?\"", "answer":0,"answers":["Kite"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The effect of the harmony of color and values in a work.", "answer":0,"answers":["Tone"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The fallacy of personifying inanimate objects, often in bad taste.", "answer":0,"answers":["Pathetic fallacy"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The famous lithograph \"The scream\" was created by which artist?", "answer":0,"answers":["Edvard Munch"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The Hardy Boys and ______?", "answer":0,"answers":["Nancy Drew"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The play \"Our Town\" is set where?", "answer":0,"answers":["Grover's Corners"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The rendering of light and shade in painting; the subtle graduations and marked variations of light and shade for dramatic effect.", "answer":0,"answers":["Chiaroscuro"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The representation of inanimate objects in painting, drawing or photography.", "answer":0,"answers":["Still life"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The Royal Opera House in London is home to which branch of the arts other than Opera?", "answer":0,"answers":["Ballet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The study of building design is ____________.", "answer":0,"answers":["Architecture"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The surrealist painter Salvador Dali was a native of which country?", "answer":0,"answers":["Spain"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The technique of producing printed designs through various methods of incising on wood or metal blocks, which are then inked and printed.", "answer":0,"answers":["Etching"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The term \"Impressionism\" was first used abusively about which artist?", "answer":0,"answers":["Claude Monet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The two races in HG Well's \"The Time Machine\" are the child-like Eloi and the subterannean ______?\"", "answer":0,"answers":["Morlocks"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"The visual and tactile quality of a work based on the particular way the materials are handled, also, the distribution of tones or shades of a single color.", "answer":0,"answers":["Texture"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This book, Oscar Wilde's only novel, was used as evidence in his sodomy trial?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Picture of Dorian Gray"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This early American statesman and inventor wrote the book, \"Fart proudly\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Benjamin Franklin"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This girl hid from the Nazis in Amsterdam.", "answer":0,"answers":["Anne frank"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This is the choice and arrangement of words and phrases in a literary work. It is the vocabulary that the author, poet or playwright uses to create style and effect in a piece of writing?", "answer":0,"answers":["Diction"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This magazine chronicled the \"Man of Bronze\" and the \"Fabulous Five\".", "answer":0,"answers":["Doc Savage"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This magazine features departments \"Picks & Pans\" and \"Chatter\"\"", "answer":0,"answers":["People"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This magazine used to boast a circulation of 7,777,777.", "answer":0,"answers":["Better homes and gardens"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This man was Time magazine's 1938 \"Man of the Year\"\"", "answer":0,"answers":["Adolf hitler"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This Romantic poet and husband of Mary Shelley drowned in a boating accident?", "answer":0,"answers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This statue was found on the Greek island of Melos in 1820.", "answer":0,"answers":["Venus de milo"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"This subject is covered in the magazine \"Bondage\" (two words)\"", "answer":0,"answers":["James bond"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Three main types of Greek columns are Doric, Ionic, and __________.", "answer":0,"answers":["Corinthian"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Tilly Trotter, Hannah Massey And Maggie Rowan Are All Characters Created By Which Novelist?", "answer":0,"answers":["Catherine Cookson"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"To what name was the Hall of Arts & Sciences changed?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Royal Albert Hall"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Under what pen name did Hector Hugh Munro write?", "answer":0,"answers":["Saki"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Water-soluble paint made from pigments and a plastic binder.", "answer":0,"answers":["Acrylic"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What are arranged in the Japanese art of Ikebana?", "answer":0,"answers":["Flowers"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What are the christian names of JK Rowling Author of the \"Harry Potter\" books?", "answer":0,"answers":["Joanne Kathleen"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What are the March Sisters names in Louisa M Alcotts \"Little Woman\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Jo, Meg Beth & Amy"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What book is the film Blade Runner based on?", "answer":0,"answers":["Do androids dream of electric sheep"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What controversial book did Germaine Greer write?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Female Eunuch"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What creatures does captain Ahab become obsessed with?", "answer":0,"answers":["Moby Dick, Great White Whale"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What dance is associated with Vienna?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Waltz"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What did A E Housemans initials stand for?", "answer":0,"answers":["Alfred Edward"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What did Jeannie C. Riley describe as \"a little Peyton Place\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Harper Valley"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What did Winston Encounter in room 101?", "answer":0,"answers":["Rats"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What do you call a picture that is made of various materials stuck together?", "answer":0,"answers":["A Collage"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What Dr Seuss character steals Christmas?", "answer":0,"answers":["Grinch"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What Dutch master painted 64 self-portraits?", "answer":0,"answers":["Rembrandt"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What famous character did Edgar Rice Burroughs create?", "answer":0,"answers":["Tarzan"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What famous gothic novel was written by Mary Shelley?", "answer":0,"answers":["Frankenstein"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What Irish playwright and author, wrote \"The Importance of Being Ernest\" and \"A Picture of Dorian Grey\" among others?\"", "answer":0,"answers":["Oscar Wilde"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is \"onomatopoeia\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["the use of words which sound like the event they describe, such as bang."],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is an Icelandic epic called?", "answer":0,"answers":["Saga"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the art of tracing designs and making impressions of them called?", "answer":0,"answers":["Lithography"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the ballet term for spinning on one foot?", "answer":0,"answers":["A Piroutte"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the earliest known drawing medium?", "answer":0,"answers":["Charcoal"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the fourth book in the \"Harry Potter\" series?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Goblet Of Fire"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the most performed opera in the UK?", "answer":0,"answers":["La Boheme"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the name given to the painting medium involving egg yolks?", "answer":0,"answers":["Tempera"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the name of Colin Dexter's fictional detective?", "answer":0,"answers":["Inspector Morse"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the name of Gandalf's horse?", "answer":0,"answers":["Shadowfax"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the name of Hamlet's tragic admirer?", "answer":0,"answers":["Ophelia"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the name of the 7th and final \"Harry Potter\" Book?", "answer":0,"answers":["Harry Potter & The Deathly Hallows"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the name of the bird in the Peanuts Strip?", "answer":0,"answers":["Woodstock"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the name of the main character in Homer's Odyssey?", "answer":0,"answers":["Odysseus"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], question":"What is the name of the Russian National Ballet\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Kirov Ballet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the nationality of Picasso?", "answer":0,"answers":["Spanish"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the opposite of an utopia?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dystopia"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the second best-selling book of all time?", "answer":0,"answers":["Quotations from the Works of Chairman Mao Tse-Tung"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What is the surname of Cathy in \"Wuthering Heights\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Earnshaw"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What nationality was Jospeh Conrad?", "answer":0,"answers":["Polish"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What other name does Stephen King write under?", "answer":0,"answers":["Richard Bachman"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What play by Shakespeare features the following characters: Cornwall, Gloucester, Regan, and Goneril?", "answer":0,"answers":["King Lear"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What publication was subtitled The What's New Magazine?", "answer":0,"answers":["Popular Science"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What rank was Biggles?", "answer":0,"answers":["Major"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What school of poets was john donne attributed to?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Metaphysical Poets"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What series has Robert Jordan written?", "answer":0,"answers":["Wheel of Time"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What shakespearean play features the line: \"A plague on both your houses\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Romeo and Juliet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What shakespearean play refers to the date of epiphany?", "answer":0,"answers":["Twelfth Night"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What story features flopsy, mopsy and cottontail?", "answer":0,"answers":["Peter Rabbit"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What subject did 'Mr. Chips' teach?", "answer":0,"answers":["Latin"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What trilogy did J.R.R. Tolkien write?", "answer":0,"answers":["Lord of the Rings"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What type of animal is Rupert the bear best friend Bill?", "answer":0,"answers":["Badger"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was author George Elliots real name?", "answer":0,"answers":["Mary Ann Cross (Nee Evans)"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was Dante's last name?", "answer":0,"answers":["Alighieri"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was H.G Wells' first novel?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Time Machine"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was Lestat's last name?", "answer":0,"answers":["De Lioncourt"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was Michelangelo's first name?", "answer":0,"answers":["Michelangelo!!"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was Picasso's first name?", "answer":0,"answers":["Pablo"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was Shakespeare's first play?", "answer":0,"answers":["Henry VI"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was Shakespeare's last completed play?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Tempest"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was Sherlock Holmes most famous novel?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Hound of The Baskervilles"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was Sherlock Holmes' 7% solution in \"The Sign of Four\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Cocaine"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was the famous novel written in gaol, by John Bunyan?", "answer":0,"answers":["Pilgim's Progress"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was the name of Charles Dickens last novel, unfinished at his death?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Mystery Of Edwin Drood"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was the name of Mother Goose's son?", "answer":0,"answers":["Jack"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was the name of the author who released \"A Guide To Baby And Child Care\" In 1946?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dr Spock (No Kidding)"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was the name of William Wordworths sister?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dorothy"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was the only novel to be written by Margaret Mitchell?", "answer":0,"answers":["Gone With The Wind"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was the sequel to Louisa May Alcott's \"Little Women\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Little Men"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What was the title of the first ever James Bond novel?", "answer":0,"answers":["Casino Royale"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What were the dolls in the novel \"Valley Of The Dolls\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Pills"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What were the tree like creatures in \"The Lord Of The Rings\" called?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Ents"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What were the two cities in \"A tale of two cities\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["London and Paris"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What word is Isaac Asimov famous for coining?", "answer":0,"answers":["Robotics"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"What's Penthouse's sister publication for women?", "answer":0,"answers":["Viva"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Where is the Louvre located?", "answer":0,"answers":["Paris"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Where is the prado gallery?", "answer":0,"answers":["Madrid"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Where is the worlds largest art gallery?", "answer":0,"answers":["Paris (Lourve)"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Where might you find the \"Museum of modern art\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["New York"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Where was El Grecho born?", "answer":0,"answers":["Crete"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Where would you find \"Poets Corner\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Westminster Abbey"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Where would you find the \"Elgin Marbles\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["The British Museum"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which algerian born french authors works included \"L'Etranger & La Peste\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Albert Camus"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], question":"Which american artist is known for a portrait of his mother\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["James Whistler"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which american author wrote \"jaws\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Peter Benchley"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which american author wrote the novel \"Roots\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Alex Haley"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which antipodean opera singer sung at Prince Charles wedding to Lady Diana Spencer?", "answer":0,"answers":["Kiri Te Kanawa"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which artists name literally means \"little barrel\"?)", "answer":0,"answers":["Botticelli"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author described world war one as the \"war to end all wars\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["HG Wells"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author did Hitler acclaim as the phrophet of right wing authoritarianism?", "answer":0,"answers":["Nietzsche"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author penned the Disc-World Series of sci-fi novels?", "answer":0,"answers":["Terry Pratchett"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author wrote \"The Sound & The Fury\", \"The Wild Palms\", and \"As I Lay Dying\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["William Faulkner"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author wrote \"The Spy That Came In From The Cold\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["John Le Carre"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author wrote novels apon which the tv series \"All creatures great & small\" was based?", "answer":0,"answers":["James Herriot"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author wrote the \"Just So Stories\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Rudyard Kipling"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author wrote the book \"Black Beauty\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Anna Sewell"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author wrote the books \"The Shining\" and \"Pet Semetary\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Stephen King"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which author's father was imprisoned for debt?", "answer":0,"answers":["Charles Dickens"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which book featured mister Scrooge?", "answer":0,"answers":["A Christmas Carol"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which british artist is noted for his numerous paintings of horses?", "answer":0,"answers":["George Stubbs"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which british painter frequently uses a swimming pool as a theme?", "answer":0,"answers":["David Hockney"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which celebration of the arts in held in Wales?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Eisteddfod"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which character created by Dodie Smith drove a black and white car and wore a black and white fur coat?", "answer":0,"answers":["Cruella De Vil"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which character featured in Jules Verne's \"Around The World In 80 Days\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Phileas Fogg"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which character invariably misused english words?", "answer":0,"answers":["Mrs Malaprop"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which character is the most famous creation of James Matthew Barrie?", "answer":0,"answers":["Peter Pan"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which characters were the longest running in the comic \"The Beano\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Lord Snooty And His Pals"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which colour followed Picasso's blue period?", "answer":0,"answers":["Pink"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which decorative style was popular in the 1920's and 1930's?", "answer":0,"answers":["Art Deco"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which Em Forster novel features the Schlegal sisters?", "answer":0,"answers":["Howards End"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which english author created Horatio Hornblower?", "answer":0,"answers":["C.S. Forester"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which english writer divided his novels into 3 categories, novels of \"character & environment\", \"romances & fantasies\" and \"novels of ingenuity\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Thomas Hardy"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book begins with the line \"Marley was dead, to begin with. There was no doubt about that\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["A Christmas Carol"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book begins with the line \"Not long ago, there lived in London a young married couple of Dalmatian dogs named Pongo and Misses Pongo\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["101 Dalmations"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book begins with the line \"On January 6, 1482, the people of Paris were awakened by the tumultuous clanging of all the bells in the city\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Hunchback Of Natre Damme"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book begins with the line \"The mole had been working very hard all the morning, spring-cleaning his little home\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Wind In The Willows"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book begins with the line \"When shall we three meet again, in thunder, lightening, or in rain\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Macbeth"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book contains the line \"In a hole in the ground there lived a...\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Hobbit"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book contains the line \"It is a truth universally acknowledged that a single man in possession of a good fortune must be in want of a wife\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Pride & Prejudice"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book contains the line \"It was the best of times it was the worst of times it was the age of wisdom\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["A Tale Of 2 Cities"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book contains the line \"Mr & Mrs Dursley of number 4 Privet Drive were proud to say that they were perfectly normal\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Harry Potter And The Philosophers Stone"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous book contains the line \"Once upon a time there was a little chimney sweep and his name was tom\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Water Babies"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which famous sculptor was refused entry tothe french academy 3 times?", "answer":0,"answers":["August Rodin"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which former jockey specialises in novels concerning horse racing?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dick Francis"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which french authors novel germinal depicts life in a mining community?", "answer":0,"answers":["Emile Zola"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which gallery has exhibitions In London and St Ives, Cornwall?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Tate Gallery"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which Gilbert and Sullivan Opera is about the Emperor of Japan?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Mikado"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which is the largest museum in the world?", "answer":0,"answers":["Louvre"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which is the only book written by Margaret Mitchell?", "answer":0,"answers":["Gone With The Wind"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which Literary Character Had A Dog Called Bulls Eye?", "answer":0,"answers":["Bill Sykes (Oliver!)"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which member of the Monty Python team wrote children's books about \"Erik The Viking\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Terry Jones"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which movement spanned the period from the 17th century to the early 18th?", "answer":0,"answers":["Baroque"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which Nobel prize winner wrote \"a history of the english speaking peoples\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Winston Churchill"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which novel by Mary Shelley was subtitled \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Frankenstein"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which novel by Michael Crichton was \"best selling paperback\" in 1993?", "answer":0,"answers":["Jurassic Park"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which novel deals with the events of one day in dublin in june 1904?", "answer":0,"answers":["Ulysses By James Joyce"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which novel features Perks the station porter?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Railway Children"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which novel was originally going to be titled Elinor And Marianne?", "answer":0,"answers":["Sense And Sensibility"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which of Jane Austens?", "answer":0,"answers":["Persuasion"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which of the Bronte Sisters married the reverend A.B. Nicholls in 1854?", "answer":0,"answers":["Charlotte"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which outlaw rode a horse called Black Bess?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dick Turpin"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which painter is noted for his works depicting the Moulin Rouge?", "answer":0,"answers":["Toulouse- Lautrec"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which painter reputedly cut of his own ear?", "answer":0,"answers":["Vincent Van Goch"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which poet preceded Ted Hughes as poet laureate?", "answer":0,"answers":["Sir John Betjeman"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which poet wrote no verse during his time as poet laureate?", "answer":0,"answers":["William Wordsworth"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which poet, in his \"Elegy Written in a Country Churchyard\" told us that \"Full many a flower is born to blush unseen / And waste its sweetnes on the desert air.\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Thomas Gray"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which publishing company was founded in London in 1935 by Allen Lane?", "answer":0,"answers":["Penguin"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which school did Billy Bunter attend?", "answer":0,"answers":["Greyfriars"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which science fiction story centres around alien children in a village?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Midwitch Cuckoos"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which sculptor produced a lobster telephone?", "answer":0,"answers":["Salvador Dali"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which Shakespeare play contains the line 'if music be the food of love play on''?", "answer":0,"answers":["Twelfth Night"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which Shakespeare play opens with the 3 Witches?", "answer":0,"answers":["Macbeth"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which shakespearean character has the most lines?", "answer":0,"answers":["Hamlet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which shakespearean play features the line \"Now is the winter of our discontent\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Richard III"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which shakespearean play is set in the forest of Arden?", "answer":0,"answers":["As You Like It"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which St Louis born novelist and poet became a british subject in 1927?", "answer":0,"answers":["T.S. Eliot"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which Stephen King Novel Is Set At The Overlook Hotel?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Shining"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which tavern was the favourite haunt of Falstaff in Shakespear's \"Henry IV\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Boar's Head"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which Tennesee Williams play is about a Sicilian-American woman?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Rose Tattoo"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which thriller writers works include \"The Dark Eyes Of London\", \"Four Just Men and Sanders Of The River\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Edgar Wallace"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which two brothers wrote fairy stories in germany in the 19th century?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Brothers Grimm"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which US author penned the novels \"Of Mice and Men\" and \"East Of Eden\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["John Steinbeck"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which US clarinetist players real name was Arthur Jacob Shaw?", "answer":0,"answers":["Artie Shaw"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which US dramatist was once married to Marylin Monroe and penned the plays \"Death Of A Salesman\" and \"The Crucible\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Arthur Miller"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which welsh poet died of alcohol poisoning the year he publsihed his collected poems?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dylan Thomas"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which woman had more portraits painted of her than anyone else?", "answer":0,"answers":["Queen Elizabeth II"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which word created by JK Rowling gained entry into the Oxford English Dictionary In 2003?", "answer":0,"answers":["Muggle"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Which writer, archaeologist and soldier joined the RAF after the first world war and changed his name to shaw in 1927?", "answer":0,"answers":["T E Lawrence"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who co-wrote \"Yeoman Of The Guard\", \"Lolanthe And The Mikado\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Gilbert & Sullivan"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who composed the ballet (Romeo & Juliet)?", "answer":0,"answers":["Prokofiev"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who composed the ballet (The Nutcracker)?", "answer":0,"answers":["Tchaikovsky"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who composed the opera \"Oedipus Rex\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Stravinsky"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who created \"Horton the elephant\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dr. Seuss"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who created \"Maudie Frickett\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Jonathan Winters"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who created \"The Saint\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Leslie Charteris"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who created Lord Peter Wimsey?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dorothy L Sayers"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who created Sherlock Holmes?", "answer":0,"answers":["Sir Arthur Conan Doyle"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who created the character Adrian Mole?", "answer":0,"answers":["Sue Towsend"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who created Winnie the Pooh?", "answer":0,"answers":["A. A. Milne"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who designed the album sleeve for The Rolling Stones LP \"Sticky Fingers\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Andy Warhol"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who did author Leslie Charteris create?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Saint"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who did Macduff kill?", "answer":0,"answers":["Macbeth"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who drew \"Drawings Of Absurd Mechanical Contrivances\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["William Heath Robinson"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who dubbed Australia \"the lucky country\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Donald Horne"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who had decieved the \"Lord of Rohan\" for a number of years?", "answer":0,"answers":["Wormtongue"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who is a successful recording artist, talented landscape artist, and author of children's books?", "answer":0,"answers":["Ricky Van Shelton"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who is associated with the address 221B Baker Street, London?", "answer":0,"answers":["Sherlock Holmes"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who is Karen Blixen better known as?", "answer":0,"answers":["Isaak Dinesen"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who is noted for his \"Nonsense Verse\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Edward Lear"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who is novelist Helen Fieldings most famous character?", "answer":0,"answers":["Bridget Jones"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who is Pips benefactor In Dickens's Great Expectations?", "answer":0,"answers":["Abel Magwitch"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who Is responsible for painting the Mona Lisa?", "answer":0,"answers":["Leonardo Da Vinci"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who is the author of \"Brave New World\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Aldous Huxley"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who is the author of \"Harry Potter\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Joan Rowling"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who Is the most famous character ever to be created by Helen Fielding?", "answer":0,"answers":["Bridget Jones"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who is the protagonist of Milton's Paradise Lost?", "answer":0,"answers":["Satan"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who killed Macbeth?", "answer":0,"answers":["Macduff"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who kills Nancy in Dickens novel \"Oliver Twist\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Bill Sykes"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who painted \"Flatford Mill\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Constable"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who painted \"Irises\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Vincent Van Gogh"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who painted \"The Blue Boy\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Gainsborough"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who painted \"The Creation Of Adam\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Michelangelo"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who painted \"The Last Supper\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Leonardo Da Vinci"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who painted the \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Leonardo da vinci"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who painted the ceiling of the Sixtine Chapel?", "answer":0,"answers":["Michelangelo"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who penned the 1999 autobiography \"Managing My Life\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Alex Ferguson"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who penned the novel \"The Pelican Brief\" that was made into a film starring Julia Roberts and Denzel Washington?", "answer":0,"answers":["John Grisham"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who said 'But, soft! what light through yonder window breaks'?", "answer":0,"answers":["Romeo"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who said \"When a man is tired of London he is tired of life\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dr Samuel Johnson"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who told stories about Brer Rabbit and Brer Fox?", "answer":0,"answers":["Uncle Remus"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who was Samuel Clemens better known as?", "answer":0,"answers":["Mark Twain"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who was the author of \"Dracula\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Bram Stoker"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"who was the first person to be buried at Poets Corner?", "answer":0,"answers":["Geoffrey Chaucer"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who was the human companion of Willow?", "answer":0,"answers":["Mad Mardigan"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who was the merchant in Shakespear's \"The Merchant Of Venice\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Antonio"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who was William Shakespear's wife?", "answer":0,"answers":["Anne Hathaway"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who was Winnie the Pooh's neighbour?", "answer":0,"answers":["Piglet"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who won a Pulitzer Prize for \"Angela's Ashes\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Frank McCourt"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who writes the discworld novels?", "answer":0,"answers":["Terry Pratchett"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"1984\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["George Orwell"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Charles Dickens"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"A Tale Of Two Cities\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Charles Dickens"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"About Tarzan\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Alice In Wonderland\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Lewis Carroll"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Animal Farm\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["George Orwell"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Brave New World\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Aldous Huxley"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Ender's Game\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Orson Scott Card"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Far From The Madding Crowd\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Thomas Hardy"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Gone With The Wind\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Margaret Mitchell"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Gone With The Wind\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Margaret Mitchell"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Charles Dickens"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Gullivers Travels\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Jonathan Swift"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Jurassic Park\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Michael Crichton"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"little lamb, who made thee\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["William Blake"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Mein Kampf\" (My Struggle)?", "answer":0,"answers":["Adolf Hitler"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Old Possums Book Of Practical Cats\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["T.S. Eliot"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["John Milton"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Psycho\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Robert Bloch"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Rendezvous with Rama\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Sir Arthur C. Clarke"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Robinsonn Crusoe\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Daniel Defoe"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Ten Little Indians?\"", "answer":0,"answers":["Agatha Christie"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Adventures Of Huckleberry Finn\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Mark Twain"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Barsetshire\" novels?", "answer":0,"answers":["Anthony Trollope"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Birds\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Daphne du Maurier"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Canterbury Tales\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Geoffrey Chaucer"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The count of Monte-Christo\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Dumas"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Female Eunuch\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Germaine Greer"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Great Gatsby\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["F. Scott Fitzgerald"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Douglas Adams"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["J.R.R. Tolkien"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Murder Of Roger Ackroyd\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Agatha Christie"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Noddy Stories\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Enid Blyton"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Rime of the Ancient Mariner?\"", "answer":0,"answers":["Samuel Taylor Coleridge"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Tennessee Williams"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["H.G. Wells"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"The Wind in the Willows\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Kenneth Grahame"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"To Kill A Mockingbird\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Harper Lee"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Valley Of The Dolls\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Jacqueline Susann"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote \"Weird Harold and Fat Albert\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Bill Cosby"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the \"Belgariad\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Leigh and David Eddings"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the \"Canterbury Tales\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Geoffrey Chaucer"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the \"Discworld\" series?", "answer":0,"answers":["Terry Pratchett"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the \"Dragonriders Of Pern\" series?", "answer":0,"answers":["Anne McCaffrey"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the \"Father Brown' crime stories?", "answer":0,"answers":["G.K. Chesterton"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the \"Gulag Archipelago\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Alexander Solzhenitsyn"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the \"Myth\" series?", "answer":0,"answers":["Robert Asprin"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the \"Noddy\" books?", "answer":0,"answers":["Enid Blyton"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the book \"A Brief History Of Time\" in 1988?", "answer":0,"answers":["Stephen Hawking"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the book \"Brave New World\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Aldous Huxley"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the book \"The Origin of Species\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Charles Darwin"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the books \"The Firm\" And \"The Pelican Brief\" Both Of Which Were Made Into Films?", "answer":0,"answers":["John Grisham"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the epic poem \"Odyssey\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Homer"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the epic poem the \"Iliad\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Homer"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the novel \"Emma\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Jane Austen"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the novel \"Jaws\", that was later turned into a blockbuster movie by Steven Spielberg?", "answer":0,"answers":["Peter Benchley"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the novel \"Lady Chatterly's Lover\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["DH Lawrence"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the novel \"Silence Of The Lambs\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Thomas Harris"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the novel \"The Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr Hyde\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Stevenson"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the novels \"About A Boy\", \"How To Be Good\" and \"High Fidelity\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Nick Hornby"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the novels \"Slaughterhouse Five\" and \"Breakfast Of Champions\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Kurt Vonnegut"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the novels \"The Hunt For Red October\" And \"Clear And Present Danger\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Tom Clancy"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the opera \"The Flying Dutchman\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Wagner"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the play \"Hay Fever\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Noel Coward"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the play \"The Mousetrap\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Agatha Christie"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the shortest ever letter?", "answer":0,"answers":["Victor Hugo"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the \"Threepenny\" opera?", "answer":0,"answers":["Bertolt Brecht"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the Tintin stories?", "answer":0,"answers":["(Georges Remi ) Herge"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote the vampire series that featured Lestat as the main character?", "answer":0,"answers":["Anne Rice"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who wrote three books under the title \"Das Kapital\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Karl Marx"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Who's last words were \"Thus with a kiss I die\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Romeo"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Whose autobiography was entitled \"Dear Me\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Peter Ustinov's"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Whose first collection of short stories entitled \"In Our Time\" was published in 1925\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Ernest Hemmingway"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Whose ghost appears at the dinner table in \"Macbeth\"?", "answer":0,"answers":["Banquo's"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Whose life was the subject of James Boswell's biography, published in 1791?", "answer":0,"answers":["Samuel Johnson"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Whose smile remained after the rest of it had vanished?", "answer":0,"answers":["The Cheshire Cat's"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Whose works the \"Ballad Of Reading Gaol\" and \"De Profundis\" were written from his experiences in prison?", "answer":0,"answers":["Oscar Wilde"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"With what art movement was Salvador Dali associated?", "answer":0,"answers":["Surrealism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Womens magazine launched by New York in the 70's.", "answer":0,"answers":["Ms"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"Works of a culturally homogenous people without formal training, generally according to regional traditions and involving crafts.", "answer":0,"answers":["Folk art"],"source":""}
]
